msccruisesusa.com 2010-12-29

# MSC Cruises (USA) : Privacy Policy

**_Company Privacy Policy_** **__**At MSC Cruises (hereinafter MSC), we are committed to protecting your personal information that you share with us through the Internet.This statement sets forth our privacy policy regarding information you provide to us through the use of our Web site. This statement also provides you with information on how to prevent your personal information from being collected or shared when you visit our Web site, respond to our Web-based promotions or send us an e-mail.

Children Under the Age of Eighteen: our site is not intended for use of children under the age of eighteen without express parental consent. We recommend that minors not enter any personally identifiable information through our web site.

 **The information we gather:**   
We collect information about you through two principal means: through technology (for example IP addresses and cookies) and through your voluntary submission of information. 

1\. Non-personally Identifiable Information. Using technology, our sites can collect information about the type of browser you are using, your operating system and your IP address information using technology. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer and is recognized by web technology whenever you are surfing the Internet. None of this information is considered personally identifiable information. We also use cookies and other technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information for a variety of purposes, such as to improve the design and content of our website and to enable us to provide a more personalized experience when you browse the Internet. Most industry-standard Web browsers have an option that allows you to turn off all cookies or have your computer inform you each time that a request to place a cookie is being made. If you turn cookies off (or refuse to accept a request to place a cookie), you may not have access to some features on our Websites and some of our services, such as purchasing a cruise or being automatically recognized as a loyalty member, may not function properly. We may provide aggregate non-personally identifiable information to third parties (such as marketers, ad server companies and advertisers) that make use of general customer data. We may also share that information with concessionaires aboard our vessels and other third parties. MSC is not liable for information that is inaccurate due to technical defects in software used on our Web sites, whether induced by our systems or by software provided by third parties. 

2\. Personally Identifiable Information. You can use the majority of our Web sites without being required to divulge any personally identifiable information to us. To participate in or use some of the activities available on our sites (such as purchasing a cruise, entering a contest or contacting us) you may be required to provide certain personally identifiable information (such as your name and e-mail address). In addition, in connection with some activities such as purchasing a cruise, we collect additional personally identifiable information such as your date of birth, street and billing address, and credit card number. When corresponding with you via e-mail, we may use a variety of technologies, such as "clear gifs" or "web beacons", to let us know, among other things, whether you received and opened our e-mail. The clear gif included in the e-mail may establish a cookie on your system that further allows us to tailor information to fit your personal interests. MSC will not trade, sell or share such personally identifiable information for use by any third parties unless we have informed you, been authorized by you or are required by law to do so. In addition, such personally identifiable information shall not be disclosed to third parties unless we have informed you, been authorized by you or are required by law to do so. The term "third parties" does not include any subsidiaries or affiliates of MSC, service providers or vendors acting on MSC's behalf or travel agents or the purchaser of substantially all of the assets of MSC or a subsidiary or affiliate of MSC. Our policy is to require that third parties keep that information confidential. We reserve the right to disclose personally identifiable information, without notice, if we believe that such action is necessary to defend and protect the rights or property of MSC and its family of Web sites or to protect the personal safety of users of MSC, its Web sites or the public. Your credit card number is used to process your request for products or services and will not be shared with third parties that are not involved with the transaction.

 **How we use the information gathered:**   
• We use the information that you share with us for these purposes:   
• To provide the products, services or membership benefits you request;   
• To improve the content of our site and enhance your cruise planning experience; To ensure proper billing;   
• To measure consumer demand or interest in various offerings; and   
• For marketing and promotional purposes, including to provide you with information about products and services offered by MSC and its subsidiaries and affiliates. 

Our Web sites often provide links to resources that we believe may be useful. These links will lead you to Web sites operated by third parties that operate under different privacy policies. We encourage you to review those privacy policies, as we have no control over information you may submit to those third parties.   
Our web sites may use third parties, such as ad server companies, to present or serve advertisements that you may see on our web site. Our websites may also include advertisements placed by third parties. Our privacy policy does not cover any information collected by those third parties nor does it cover how they may use such information.

 **How do we protect your information** :   
Security for all personally identifiable information is extremely important to us. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the correct usage of information, we monitor and adjust our physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. Unfortunately, we cannot guarantee that data transmitted over the Internet will always be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products and services, and you do so at your own risk. Upon receipt of your transmission, we strive to ensure the security of that information in our systems.

 **Privacy policy updates** :   
By using our Web sites, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy. MSC reserves the right to modify, alter or otherwise update this policy at any time. Visitors are encouraged to review this policy from time to time to stay abreast of any changes. Your continued use of our Web sites following the posting of any changes to this policy means you accept those changes. 

The information you provide could be used by MSC to send marketing or other materials to you and may be transferred to travel agents or other travel professionals to enable them to send you information via email and US mail. 

By entering your information here you consent to such use of the information you submit through this web site.

 **Questions or comments?** **  
**If you have any further questions or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please send us an e-mail with your questions or comments.

 **Changing Your Personal Information?**   
If you would like to update or change your personal information, send us an email so that we can maintain an accurate database in order to better serve your needs.

 **Removing yourself from MSC mailing and/or Email lists?**   
You as our consumer always have the choice to remove your name from our mailing or other marketing list(s).  In order to be taken off of our mailing list, please do one of the two following options: 

1) Follow the instructions in communications received from us;   
2) Send an email to

[info@msccruisesusa.com](mailto:info@msccruisesusa.com) indicating you wish to be removed from our list.

  * Data controller
  * Granting access to personal data
  * Data processing methods 
  * Data processing purposes
  * Cookies
  * Data security
  * Suggestions and queries

## Data controller

The controller of any personal data provided while visiting the site is: 

MSC Crociere S.p.A.,   
Via Agostino Depretis 31, Naples (Italy),   
tel. +39-081-7942 111

## Granting access to personal data

In general, your visits to the site will remain completely anonymous, as you will not be asked to insert any personal data to access the information published. However, in order to access a number of further services (e.g. requesting a catalogue, registering for our newsletter, etc.) or to receive a reply to any queries made (e.g. information requests), you could be asked to provide some data or MSC could come into possession of same (e.g. your email address in the event of your sending MSC a message).

## Data processing methods 

Any personal data freely communicated to MSC via the website or by any other means (e.g. email, telephone and/or fax) will be processed in compliance with the Italian Privacy Code and the relevant European Directives.   
Indeed, MSC's primary commitment is to guarantee and respect the privacy of its customers and, in general, of all visitors to the MSC website. In the event of not granting MSC access to your personal data or of not authorising the processing of same, MSC may find itself unable to provide the services and/or information requested. All data provided will be processed in an automatic, computerised and/or manual manner, for the time required to achieve the purposes for which they were collected.

## Data processing purposes

1\. Compulsory: in the event of your personal data being collected to fulfil obligations and provide services relating to a stipulated contract (e.g. enrolment in the MSC Club), you will be required to provide all necessary personal data (e.g. name, surname, place and date of birth, email, etc.), which will be processed with the aim of executing the relating contractual services. To this end, the Privacy Code does not require you to authorise the processing of your personal data. 

2\. Optional: whenever expressly authorised by you, your personal data will also be processed for the promotional purposes of MSC and/or other associate or controlled companies (e.g. to send newsletters by email), for market research and with the aim of improving our services and the contents of our website.

Your personal data will not be communicated to third parties, except whenever expressly authorised by you, whenever required to fulfil contractual obligations, whenever required by MSC to fulfil legal obligations or whenever otherwise expressly allowed by law. In any other case, your data will not be disclosed.   
The site's software, however, might acquire personal data whose transmission is implicit in the use of internet communication protocols. The collection of such data does not in itself enable user identification. However, by its very nature - through elaborations and associations with data held by third parties - this data might enable user identification.   
This data category includes IP addresses or domain names of the computers used to connect to the site, as well as other parameters relating to the operating system and the type of browser adopted by the user.   
This data is used for the sole purpose of collecting anonymous statistics on the use of the website, or to check that the site functions correctly. Said data may also be used to ascertain liability in the event of IT crimes against the site or perpetrated via the site. Except in the above cases, web data will not be stored for more than 7 days.

## Cookies

The site might also make use of cookies, for the exclusive purpose of providing a specific service requested by the user or of granting access to an area of the website that would otherwise be forbidden. In these cases alone, said data will be used – merely for the time required – to transmit the relevant information and/or provide the specific service requested by the user.   
In any case, most browsers allow users to block cookies or to inform the user whenever a cookie is required. Users may choose to avail of said options, however in this case they will not be able to make use of the specific services requested or to access specific areas of the website where such information is required.

## Data security

In order to avoid the loss of data, unlawful or incorrect usage of same and unauthorised access, MSC regularly checks and updates its physical, electronic and logical security measures. However, unfortunately MSC cannot guarantee the secure transmission of data via the internet. As a result, notwithstanding our utmost commitment to ensure security, MSC cannot guarantee and ensure the security of the information transmitted to us via the internet, also due to circumstances and systems outside our control. Therefore, data is transmitted at your own risk, on the understanding that, once transmission is complete, MSC accepts all responsibility as regards security as provded under the above terms. The site might contain links to other internet sites deemed useful for users or relating to third party advertising. These resources might operate under the control of third parties, adopting different privacy policies. Therefore, MSC asks that you check the privacy policies of said third parties, as MSC has no control over any information provided by them.

The use of our website implies your acceptance of the present privacy policy. MSC reserves the right to amend or update this informative report at any time. Users are kindly requested to reread this report from time to time, in order to keep constantly updated on its contents.

## Suggestions and queries

MSC would be delighted to receive any query or suggestion regarding our privacy policy at[cruiseinfo@msccrociere.it](mailto:cruiseinfo@msccrociere.it)
